http://www.protectamerica.com/privacy-policy

keyboard_arrow_leftProtect AmericaPlansEquipmentHow it WorksGet a Free QuoteGet a Free Quotekeyboard_arrow_leftProtect America
Get startedPlansEquipmentHow it WorksGet a Free QuoteShop NowGet helpSupportLoginHomePlansGet QuoteCall UsProtect America® Privacy PolicyEffective: May 17, 2005Last Updated: December 27, 2019Thank you for visiting the Protect America® website located at www.protectamerica.com (the "Site"). The Site is an Internet property of Protect America, Inc. ("Protect America®," "we" or "our"). This Protect America® Privacy Policy ("Privacy Policy") covers our treatment of personal information and other information that we collect when end-users ("User," "you" or "your"): (a) accesses or uses the Site; (b) accesses, downloads and/or views, as applicable, any of the: (i) links to third-party resources and/or consumer information ("Third Party Links"); (ii) informational blog posts ("Blog Posts"); and/or (iii) text, video and other information pertaining to Protect America® home security-related products, services, as well as other content featured on the Site as made available by Protect America® (the "Informational Content," and together with the Blog Posts and Third Party Links, the "Content"); (c) accesses links to Protect America's® social media pages/accounts (collectively, "Social Media Pages") featured on third-party social media websites, such as Facebook®, Instagram®, LinkedIn®, Twitter® and YouTube® (collectively, "Social Media Websites"); (d) utilizes the various contact forms made available on the Site as a means to request information pertaining to and/or order the Protect America® Security System, request tech support in connection with the Protect America® Security System or to otherwise request to be contacted by Protect America® ("Contact Services," and together with the Site, Content, Social Media Pages and Contact Services, the "Site Offerings"). Please note, if you are a resident of a European Union Member State, you are not permitted to use the Site and/or Site Offerings.Users with disabilities who wish to access this Privacy Policy in an alternative format can contact us by e-mailing us at: support@protectamerica.com; calling us at: (800) 951-5111; or sending us mail to: 3800 Quick Hill Road, Building 1-100, Austin, TX 78728.Capitalized terms not defined herein shall have the meanings set forth in the Protect America® Website Terms and Conditions ("Terms and Conditions"). If you do not agree to terms of this privacy policy in their entirety, you may not access or otherwise use the site offerings.Facebook® and Instagram® are registered trademarks of Facebook, Inc. ("Facebook"). LinkedIn® is a registered trademark of LinkedIn Corporation ("LinkedIn"). Twitter® is a registered trademark of Twitter, Inc. ("Twitter"). YouTube® is a registered trademark of Google, Inc. ("Google"). Please be advised that Protect America® is not in any way affiliated with Facebook, Google, LinkedIn or Twitter, nor are the Site Offerings endorsed, administered or sponsored by any of the foregoing entities.Your California Privacy RightsIf you are a resident of the State of California certain other privacy-related rights may apply to you, including the right to opt-out of our sale of your personal information, as well as the right to know what personal information about you we have collected, whether your personal information was shared with third-parties in the preceding year and, if so, what categories of personal information were shared, as well as the names and addresses of those third-parties. Please see our Provisions for California Residents below for a more complete description of your rights as a California resident.Privacy Policy Quick LinksBelow are links to key sections of our Privacy Policy:Your Nevada Privacy RightsPersonal Information CollectedCredit CheckUse and Sharing of Personal InformationNon-Personal Information Collection and UseCredit and/or Debit Card TransactionsSecurity of Your Personal InformationChildren's PrivacyOpt-Out/UnsubscribeDeleting, Modifying and Updating Your InformationChanges to this Privacy PolicyContact UsYour Nevada Privacy RightsIf you are a resident of the State of Nevada and would like to opt-out from the sale of your personal information to any third party data broker, please e-mail us at: support@protectamerica.com; call us at: (800) 951-5111; or send us mail to: 3800 Quick Hill Road, Building 1-100, Austin, TX 78728.Personal Information CollectedPlease see our Provisions for California Residents below for additional details regarding the categories of personal information collected. For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, "personal information" shall mean individually identifiable information from or about an individual. We collect personal information when you access certain of the Site Offerings and complete the required information request form(s) and/or otherwise provide such information to us. The information that you must supply on the form(s) may include, without limitation: (a) your full name; (b) your e-mail address; (c) your telephone number; (d) your zip code; (e) your CID/account number (where you are already a Protect America® Product account holder); (f) the last four (4) digits of your Social Security Number; and (g) any other information requested on the applicable form.Where you contact Protect America® by telephone in order to purchase the Protect America® Security System, a Protect America® representative may request additional information over the telephone including, without limitation, your: (i) full Social Security Number; (ii) credit card, debit card or other payment information; and (iii) any other information requested by the Protect America® representative.For purposes of this Privacy Policy, items (f), (i) and (ii) in the preceding paragraphs will be considered "Sensitive Information."If you call a telephone number listed on the Site, we may collect personal information from you, including your name and telephone number through caller identification and reverse call technology. We also may record the telephone conversation. We record the telephone conversation to track the performance of our advertisements and for quality assurance purposes. We do not record calls for the purpose of collecting your personal information. If we intend to record a telephone conversation with you, we will notify you before the conversation begins.Credit CheckPlease note, a basic credit check is required for approval when you attempt to order the Protect America® Security System on the website, or over the telephone from one of our representatives. In order to protect your identity and complete the credit check, Protect America® requires your Social Security Number. We use your Social Security Number to check your credit through Equifax® and, in some cases, TransUnion®. Specifically, in most cases we use Equifax Decision Power® to conduct most credit checks. When you enter your information on Step 2 of the Site-ordering process and click the "Next" button, your encrypted information is transmitted through the Equifax® system to review your credit. We recommend entering your information as well as that of your spouse/co-applicant when you are submitting your Protect America® Security System order. Once Protect America® has run your credit through the applicable credit agencies, you will receive a message to proceed with your Protect America® Security System order, and then alerted when your on-line order has been processed. Otherwise, you will be directed to call, Protect America® at: (800) 951-5111.If you have any questions regarding the aforementioned credit check and approval process, please call us toll free at: (800) 951-5111, Ext. 8247.Equifax® and Equifax Decision Power® are registered trademarks of Equifax, Inc. ("Equifax"). TransUnion® is a registered trademark of TransUnion LLC ("TransUnion"). Please be advised that Protect America® is not in any way affiliated with Equifax or TransUnion, nor are the Site Offerings endorsed, administered or sponsored by any of the foregoing entities.Use and Sharing of Personal InformationPlease see our Provisions for California Residents below for details regarding our uses and sharing of personal informationOther than as set forth in this Privacy Policy, or where you separately provide your express consent, Protect America® will never share, sell, rent, exchange or barter your personal information to or with any third-party for financial gain or marketing purposes. By making that personal information available to Protect America®, you grant Protect America® the right, subject to applicable state and federal law, to use that personal information to contact you by telephone, e-mail and to send you various marketing messages that contain promotional offers from Protect America® that Protect America® believes may be of interest to you. If you wish to stop receiving future communications from us, please follow the instructions at the end of each such marketing message, you may "opt-out" on our unsubscribe page or use any of the other options available in the "Opt-Out/Unsubscribe" section below.Where you submit personal information, we use the personal information that you make available to facilitate the delivery of the applicable Site Offerings and Protect America® Security System to you, including to respond to any inquiries and/or tech requests made by you. You also agree that we may contact you at any time with updates and/or any other information that we may deem appropriate for you to receive in connection with your continued use of the Site Offerings and/or Protect America® Security System, and to keep you informed of our other products and services.We may also employ other companies and individuals to perform certain functions on our behalf. Examples include the credit check referenced above, processing credit card and other payment transactions, sending direct and electronic mail, removing duplicate information from User lists, analyzing data and providing marketing analysis. The agents performing these limited functions on our behalf shall have access to our Users' personal information (including Sensitive Information, where applicable) as needed to perform these functions for us, but we do not permit them to use User personal information for other purposes.We will also use your personal information for customer service, to provide you with information that you may request, to customize your experience with the Site Offerings and/or Protect America® Security System and/or to contact you for market research purposes. We may also use your personal information for internal business purposes, such as analyzing and managing our service offerings including, without limitation, the Site Offerings and/or Protect America® Security System. We may also combine the information we have gathered about you with information from other sources.By submitting your personal information by and through the Site Offerings, you agree that such act constitutes an inquiry and/or application for purposes of the Amended Telemarketing Sales Rule (16 CFR §310 et seq.), as amended from time to time (the "Rule") and applicable state do-not-call regulations. As such, notwithstanding that your telephone number may be listed on the Federal Trade Commission's Do-Not-Call List, and/or on applicable state do-not-call lists, we retain the right to contact you via telemarketing in accordance with the Rule and applicable state do-not-call regulations.Where you provide "prior express consent" within the meaning of the Telephone Consumer Protection Act (47 USC § 227), and its implementing regulations adopted by the Federal Communications Commission (47 CFR § 64.1200), as amended from time-to-time ("TCPA"), you consent to receive, from Protect America®, telephone calls, including artificial voice calls, pre-recorded messages and/or calls (including text alerts via SMS text messages delivered via automated technology, to the telephone number(s) that you provided. Please note that you are not required to provide this consent in order to obtain access to the Site Offerings, and your consent simply allows Protect America® to contact you via these means. Please be advised that by agreeing to this Privacy Policy, you are obligated to immediately inform us if and when the telephone number that you have previously provided to us changes. Without limiting the foregoing, if you: (a) have your telephone number reassigned to another person or entity; (b) give up your telephone number so that it is no longer used by you; (c) port your telephone number to a landline or vice versa; or (d) otherwise stop using that telephone number for any reason (collectively "Phone Number Change"), you agree that you shall promptly notify Protect America® of the Phone Number Change via e-mail at: support@protectamerica.com, or by using one of the methods set forth in the "Contact Us" section below.We reserve the right to release current or past personal information (including Sensitive Information): (i) in the event that we believe that the Site Offerings are being or have been used in violation of the Terms and Conditions or to commit unlawful acts; (ii) if the information is subpoenaed; provided, however, that, where permitted by applicable law, we shall provide you with e-mail notice, and opportunity to challenge the subpoena, prior to disclosure of any personal information pursuant to a subpoena; or (iii) if we are sold, merge with a third-party, are acquired or are the subject of bankruptcy proceedings; provided, however, that if Protect America® is involved in a bankruptcy proceeding, merger, acquisition or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via e-mail and/or a prominent notice on the Site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices that you may have regarding your personal information.You hereby consent to the disclosure of any record or communication to any third-party when we, in our sole discretion, determine the disclosure to be required by applicable law, including sharing your e-mail address with third-parties for suppression purposes in compliance with the CAN-SPAM Act of 2003, as amended from time to time, and other e-mail marketing laws. Users should also be aware that courts of equity, such as U.S. Bankruptcy Courts, might have the authority under certain circumstances to permit personal information to be shared or transferred to third-parties without permission.Non-Personal Information Collection and UsePlease see our Provisions for California Residents below for more details regarding the categories and types of non-personal information collectedComputer IP Addresses/Browser Type We may collect certain non-personally identifiable information about you and your desktop computer when you visit many of the pages of the Site. This non-personally identifiable information includes, without limitation, the type of browser that you use (e.g., Safari, Chrome, Internet Explorer), your IP address, the type of operating system that you use (e.g., Windows or iOS) and the domain name of your Internet service provider (e.g., Verizon, AT&T). We use the non-personally identifiable information that we collect to improve the design and content of the Site Offerings and to enable us to personalize your Internet experience. We also may use this information in the aggregate to analyze usage of the Site Offerings.Credit and/or Debit Card TransactionsProtect America® utilizes third-party service providers to provide credit and debit card payment processing services. If you choose to purchase a Protect America® Security System, the credit or debit card information provided will be shared with our contracted third-party payment processing service provider(s). Protect America® requires that its third-party payment processing service provider(s) has/have in place privacy policies and practices consistent with this Privacy Policy; provided, however, that we cannot guarantee the privacy practices of our third-party payment processing service provider(s).CookiesWhen a User visits the Site, we send one (1) or more cookies and/or gif files (collectively, "Cookies") to assign an anonymous, unique identifier to the applicable User's computer and/or mobile device, as applicable. A Cookie is a piece of data stored on your hard drive containing non-personally identifiable information about you. Cookies have many benefits to enhance your experience on the Site, as applicable. To find out more about Cookies, please visit www.cookiecentral.com. We use Cookies to improve the quality of the Site Offerings, including for storing User preferences and tracking Site usage (such as pages opened and length of stay at the Site, as applicable).Most Internet browsers are initially set up to accept Cookies, but you can reset your browser to refuse all Cookies or to indicate when a Cookie is being sent. To disable and reject certain Cookies, follow the instructions associated with your Internet browser. To manage Flash Cookies, please click here: http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html. Even in the case where a User rejects a Cookie, he or she may still use the Site Offerings; provided, however, that certain functions of the Site Offerings may be impaired or rendered inoperable if the use of Cookies is disabled. We reserve the right to retain Cookie data indefinitely.Behavioral TrackingProtect America® and its third-party partners use Cookies, pixels and other tracking technology (collectively, "Tracking Technology") to analyze trends, administer the Site, track Users' movements around the Site and to gather demographic information about our User base as a whole. In addition, we partner with a third-party to use Tracking Technology in connection with the display of advertising on our Site and to manage the serving of our advertising on other websites. Our third-party partners may use Tracking Technology to gather information about your activities on the Site and other websites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests.If you wish to opt-out of having this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking here (or if you are located in the European Union, please click here). In addition, Users may be able to disable some, but not all, of this tracking activity by utilizing the "Do Not Track" setting or similar options within most major Internet browsers. Further, Users may be able to opt-out of this form of tracking utilizing the options made available by the Network Advertising Initiativeor Digital Advertising Alliance.Please note that opting out of this tracking activity does not opt you out of being served advertising. Even where you opt out of this tracking activity, you will continue to receive generic ads.Cross Device TrackingProtect America® tracks Users' use of the Site Offerings across various devices, including your personal computer and mobile device, in order to optimize and personalize your Site Offerings experience. Protect America® may collect certain of your personal information across various devices. If you would like to opt-out of having your use of the Site Offerings tracked across multiple devices, please e-mail us at: support@protectamerica.com. Please be advised that where you opt-out of having your use of the Site Offerings tracked across devices, you may need to upload certain information multiple times and/or input your log-in information multiple times.Aggregate DataProtect America® reserves the right to transfer and/or sell aggregate or group data about Users of the Site Offerings for lawful purposes. Aggregate or group data is data that describes the demographics, usage and other characteristics of Users as a group, without disclosing personally identifiable information.Social Media Websites and WidgetsIf you engage in any interaction with Protect America®, other Users or any third-party on any Social Media Pages, you should be aware that: (a) the personal information that you submit by and through such Social Media Pages can be read, collected and/or used by other users of these websites/services (depending on your privacy settings associated with your accounts with the applicable Social Media Websites), and could be used to send you unsolicited messages or otherwise to contact you without your consent or desire; and (b) where Protect America® responds to any interaction on such Social Media Pages, your account name/handle may be viewable by any and all members/users of Protect America's® social media accounts. We are not responsible for the personal information that you choose to submit on any Social Media Websites.In addition, the Site contains Social Media Website widgets and buttons ("Widgets"), such as the Facebook® and Twitter® share buttons. These Widgets may collect your IP address, as well as which page you are visiting on our Site, and may set a Cookie on your browser to enable the Widget to function properly. The Widgets are owned and operated by the applicable Social Media Websites. The Social Media Websites operate independently from Protect America®, and we are not responsible for such Social Media Websites' interfaces or privacy or security practices.Your interactions with the Social Media Pages and Widgets are governed by the privacy policies of the applicable Social Media Websites. We encourage you to review the privacy policies and settings of the Social Media Pages and/or Widgets with which you interact to help you understand those Social Media Websites' respective privacy practices. If you have questions about the security and privacy settings of any Social Media Pages and/or Widgets that you use, please refer to the applicable Social Media Website's privacy notices or policies.Third-Party WebsitesThis Site may contain links to third-party owned and/or operated websites including, without limitation, Social Media Websites, as well as the websites of other third parties. Protect America® is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites. In some cases, you may be able to make a purchase through one of these third-party websites. In these instances, you may be required to provide certain information, such as a credit card number, to register or complete a transaction at such website. These third-party websites have separate privacy and data collection practices and Protect America® has no responsibility or liability relating to them.Security of Your Personal InformationWe endeavor to safeguard and protect our Users' personal information. When Users make personal information available to us, their personal information is protected both online and offline (to the extent that we maintain any personal information offline). Where our registration/application process prompts Users to enter Sensitive Information (such as Social Security Number and credit card information), and when we store and transmit such Sensitive Information, that information is encrypted with advanced TLS (Transport Layer Security).Access to your personal information is strictly limited, and we take reasonable security measures to ensure that your personal information is not accessible to the public. All of our Users' personal information is restricted in our offices, as well as the offices of our third-party service providers. Only employees or third-party agents who need User personal information to perform a specific job are granted access to User personal information. Our employees are dedicated to ensuring the security and privacy of all User personal information. Employees not adhering to our firm policies are subject to disciplinary action. The servers that we store User personal information on are kept in a secure physical environment. We also have security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of personal information under our control.Please be advised, however, that while we take every reasonable precaution available to protect your data, no storage facility, technology, software, security protocols or data transmission over the Internet or via wireless networks can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Computer hackers that circumvent our security measures may gain access to certain portions of your personal information, and technological bugs, errors and glitches may cause inadvertent disclosures of your personal information; provided, however, that any attempt to breach the security of the network, our servers, databases or other hardware or software may constitute a crime punishable by law. For the reasons mentioned above, we cannot warrant that your personal information will be absolutely secure. Any transmission of data at or through the Site, other Site Offerings or otherwise via the Internet or wireless networks, is done at your own risk.In compliance with applicable federal and state laws, we shall notify you and any applicable regulatory agencies in the event that we learn of an information security breach with respect to your personal information. You will be notified via e-mail in the event of such a breach. Please be advised that notice may be delayed in order to address the needs of law enforcement, determine the scope of network damage, and to engage in remedial measures.If you have any questions about our security practices associated with the Site, you can email us at: webmaster@protectamerica.com.Children's PrivacyPlease see our Provisions for California Residents below for more details regarding the personal information of minors. Visitors under eighteen (18) years of age are not permitted to use and/or submit their personal information at the Site. Protect America® does not knowingly solicit or collect information from visitors under eighteen (18) years of age.Opt-Out/UnsubscribePlease see our Provisions for California Residents below for instructions on how California Residents can opt-out of the sale of their personal information to third parties. To opt-out of receiving e-mail and other forms of communication from us, you can: (a) follow the instructions included in the applicable e-mail message or other communication; (b) follow the instructions on our unsubscribe page; or (c) e-mail us at: support@protectamerica.com.Notwithstanding the foregoing, we may continue to contact you for the purpose of communicating information relating to your request for Site Offerings, as well as to respond to any inquiry or request made by you. To opt-out of receiving Site Offerings-related and/or inquiry response-related messages from Protect America®, you must cease requesting and/or utilizing the Site Offerings and/or cease submitting inquiries to Protect America®, as applicable.Deleting, Modifying and Updating Your InformationPlease see our Provisions for California Residents below for instructions on how California Residents can access and/or delete personal information that we have collected. At your request, we will: (a) inform you of what personal information we have on file for you; (b) amend the personal information that we have on file for you; and/or (c) remove personal information that you have provided to us, or that we have otherwise collected. You may do so by e-mailing us at: support@protectamerica.com. We ask individual Users to identify themselves and the information requested to be accessed, corrected or removed before processing such requests, and, to the extent permitted by applicable law, we may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive or systematic, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others or would be extremely impractical (for instance, requests concerning information residing on backup tapes).Please be advised that deleting your personal information may terminate your access to certain of the Site Offerings. If you wish to continue using the full complement of Site Offerings, you may not be able to delete all of the personal information that we have on file for you.Please be further advised that, after you delete your personal information, residual copies may take a period of time before they are deleted from our active servers and may remain in our backup systems.Transfer of Personal Information InternationallyIf you are visiting the Site from a country other than the country in which our servers are located, your communications with us may result in the transfer of information across international boundaries. By visiting the Site and/or otherwise communicating electronically with us, you consent to such transfers. Even if your jurisdiction does not have the same privacy laws as the jurisdiction where our servers are located, we will treat your information as subject to the protections described in this Privacy Policy.Changes to this Privacy PolicyProtect America® reserves the right to change or update this Privacy Policy at any time by posting a notice on the Site that we are changing our Privacy Policy. If the manner in which we use personal information changes, Protect America® will notify Users by: (a) sending the modified policy to our Users via e-mail; and/or (b) by any other reasonable means acceptable under applicable state and federal law. You will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in this different manner and we will only use your information in this different manner where you opt-in to such use.Contact UsIf you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or our privacy practices in general you may e-mail us as at: support@protectamerica.com; call us at: (800) 951-5111; or send us mail to: 3800 Quick Hill Road, Building 1-100, Austin, TX 78728.Filing a Complaint with the Federal Trade CommissionTo file a complaint regarding our privacy practices, please Click Here.Privacy Notice for California ResidentsThese Provisions for California Residents (“Provisions”) supplement, and do not limit in any way, the Privacy Policy set forth above. These Provisions apply solely to residents of the State of California (“CA Users”). We adopt these Provisions in compliance with the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 (“CCPA”) and other applicable California State privacy laws. Any terms defined in the CCPA have the same meaning when used in these Provisions. Users with disabilities who wish to access these Provisions in an alternative format can contact us by emailing us at: support@protectamerica.com; calling us at: (800) 951-5111; or sending us U.S. mail to: Protect America, 3800 Quick Hill Road, Building 1-100, Austin, TX 78728.Categories of Information We CollectWe collect information that identifies, relates to, describes, references, is capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, with a particular CA User or device (“personal information”). In particular, we have collected the following categories of personal information from CA Users within the last twelve (12) months:CategoryExamplesCollectedA. Identifiers.A real name, alias, postal address, unique personal identifier, online identifier, Internet Protocol address, email address, account name, telephone number, or other similar identifiers.YESB. Personal information categories listed in the California Customer Records statute (Cal. Civ. Code § 1798.80(e)).A name, signature, Social Security number, physical characteristics or description, postal address, telephone number, passport number, driver's license or State identification card number, insurance policy number, education, employment, employment history, bank account number, credit card number, debit card number, or any other financial information, medical information, or health insurance information. Some personal information included in this category may overlap with other categories.YESC. Protected classification characteristics under California or federal law.Age (40 years or older), race, color, ancestry, national origin, citizenship, religion or creed, marital status, medical condition, physical or mental disability, sex (including gender, gender identity, gender expression, pregnancy or childbirth and related medical conditions), sexual orientation, veteran or military status, genetic information (including familial genetic information).NOD. Commercial information.Records of personal property, products or services purchased, obtained, or considered, or other purchasing or consuming histories or tendencies.NOE. Biometric information.Genetic, physiological, behavioral, and biological characteristics, or activity patterns used to extract a template or other identifier or identifying information, such as, fingerprints, faceprints, and voiceprints, iris or retina scans, keystroke, gait, or other physical patterns, and sleep, health, or exercise data.NOF. Internet or other similar network activity.Browsing history, search history, information on a CA User's interaction with a website, application or advertisement.YESG. Geolocation data.Physical location or movements.NOH. Sensory data.Audio, electronic, visual, thermal, olfactory, or similar information.NOI. Professional or employment-related information.Current or past job history or performance evaluations.NOJ. Non-public education information (per the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (20 U.S.C. Section 1232g, 34 C.F.R. Part 99)).Education records directly related to a student maintained by an educational institution or party acting on its behalf, such as grades, transcripts, class lists, student schedules, student identification codes, student financial information, or student disciplinary records.NOK. Inferences drawn from other personal information.Profile reflecting a person's preferences, characteristics, psychological trends, predispositions, behavior, attitudes, intelligence, abilities, and aptitudes.NOPersonal information does not include:Publicly available information from government records.De-identified or aggregated CA User information.Information excluded from the CCPA's scope, such as:Health or medical information covered by the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA) and the California Confidentiality of Medical Information Act (CMIA) or clinical trial data;Personal information covered by certain sector-specific privacy laws, including the Fair Credit Reporting Act (FRCA), the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (GLBA) or California Financial Information Privacy Act (FIPA), and the Driver's Privacy Protection Act of 1994.We obtain the categories of personal information for which we indicated “YES” above from the following categories of sources:Directly from our CA Users. For example, from online registration forms that our CA Users submit to us, or phone calls made to our representatives, in connection with the products and/or services that we offer by and through the Site.Indirectly from our CA Users. For example, through information we collect from our CA Users in the course of providing our products and/or services to them.Directly and indirectly from activity on the Site, as well as via certain tracking technology after you leave the Site. This includes the type of browser that you use (e.g., Safari, Chrome, Internet Explorer), your IP address, the type of operating system that you use (e.g., Windows or iOS) and the domain name of your Internet Service Provider. In addition, we obtain certain Site usage details and analytics as same are collected automatically by us and our third party partners. This includes the advertisements that you click on and interact with, the pages of the Site (and other websites) visited and items purchased/added to your cart.When our CA Users interact with us on our social media accounts, including commenting on and/or liking our posts.From third-parties that interact with us in connection with the products and/or services that we offer to our CA Users. For example, third party entities that assist us in sending direct and electronic mail, removing duplicate information from CA User lists, analyzing data and providing marketing analysisFrom third-party data brokers or aggregators.From publicly availably sources, such as Internet search engines.Use of Personal InformationWe may use or disclose the personal information that we collect (including (a) your full name; (b) your e-mail address; (c) your telephone number; (d) your zip code; (e) your CID/account number (where you are already a Protect America® Product account holder); (f) your Social Security Number; and (g) your credit card and/or debit card information) for one or more of the following business purposes:To fulfill or meet the reason for which the information is provided. For example, if you provide us with personal information in connection with your purchase of the Protect America® Security System or other Protect America® products and/or services, we will use that information to process your purchase.To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us.To create, maintain, customize and secure your account with us.To conduct credit checks in connection with your purchase (or attempted purchase) of the Protect America® Security System or other Protect America® products and/or services. In particular, we use your Social Security Number to check your credit through Equifax® and, in some cases, TransUnion®.To provide you with e-mail, direct mail and telemarketing messages concerning certain Protect America® products and/or services, as well as third-party products and/or services, that we believe may be of interest to you.To deliver relevant Site content to you.To serve you relevant advertisements on the Site, and on third-party websites when you exit the Site, and to measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising that we serve.To carry out our obligations and enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us, including the Site’s Terms and Conditions.To improve the Site and better present its contents to you.For customer service purposes and to respond to inquiries from you.For testing, research, analysis and product development.As necessary or appropriate to protect our rights, property or safety, and that of our clients or others.To respond to law enforcement requests and as required by applicable law, court order, or governmental regulations.As described to you when collecting your personal information or as otherwise set forth in the CCPA.To evaluate or conduct a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution or other sale or transfer of some or all of our assets, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation or similar proceeding, in which personal information held by us is among the assets transferred.We will not collect additional categories of personal information or use the personal information we collected for materially different, unrelated or incompatible purposes without providing you with notice.Sharing Personal InformationSubject to your right to opt-out of such sharing/sale, we may share your personal information (including (a) your full name; (b) your e-mail address; (c) your telephone number; (d) your zip code; (e) your CID/account number (where you are already a Protect America® Product account holder); (f) your Social Security Number; and (g) your credit card and/or debit card information) with/to third parties for marketing purposes, as well as certain other business purposes. When we disclose personal information to a third party service provider or other entity, we enter into a contractual relationship that describes the purpose for which such third party may use the personal information and requires that third party to both keep the personal information confidential and not use it for any purpose other than the performance of its services under the applicable contract. Please note, we do not collect information from CA Users that we actually know are less than eighteen (18) years of age and we do not share or sell the personal information of CA Users that we actually know are less than eighteen (18) years of age. Without limiting the foregoing, we have not shared or sold the personal information of CA Users that we actually know are less than sixteen (16) years of age in the preceding twelve (12) months.In the preceding twelve (12) months, we have shared your personal information (including (a) your full name; (b) your e-mail address; (c) your telephone number; (d) your zip code; (e) your CID/account number (where you are already a Protect America® Product account holder); (f) your Social Security Number; and (g) your credit card and/or debit card information) (a) with third parties who purchase and/or license your personal information for marketing purposes; and (b) for the business purposes set forth above.In the preceding twelve (12) months, we have disclosed the following categories of personal information for a business purpose:Category A:Identifiers.Category B:California Customer Records personal information categories.Category F:Internet or other similar network activity.In the preceding twelve (12) months, we have sold the following categories of personal information to third parties:Category A:Identifiers.Category B:California Customer Records personal information categories.Category F:Internet or other similar network activity.We disclose your personal information for a business purpose to the following categories of third parties:Our affiliates.Service providers.Third parties who provide payment processing services in connection with the products and/or services purchased on the Site.Third parties, such as Equifax® and TransUnion®, who provide credit check services on users who purchase (or attempt to purchase) the products and/or services that are available for purchase on the Site.Third parties who purchase and/or license your personal information for marketing purposes, including: (a) providers of direct marketing services and applications, including lookup and reference, data enhancement, suppression and validation; (b) e-mail marketers; (c) telemarketers (where permitted by applicable law); and (d) direct marketers. If a third party purchaser of your personal information wants to resell it, that purchaser is required by law to provide you with explicit notice and an opportunity to opt-out of further sales.Third parties to whom you authorize us to disclose your personal information to in connection with the products and/or services that we provide to you.Your Rights and ChoicesThe CCPA provides CA Users (California residents) with specific rights regarding their personal information. This section describes your CCPA rights and explains how to exercise those rights.Opt-Out from the Sale of Your Personal InformationYou have the right to opt-out of our sale of your personal information to third parties. To exercise your right to opt-out of our sale of your personal information to third parties, please submit a verifiable CA User request to us by either:Clicking here;Emailing us at: support@protectamerica.com;Calling us at: (800) 951-5111; orSending us U.S. mail to: Protect America, 3800 Quick Hill Road, Building 1-100, Austin, TX 78728.Where you make a request to opt-out of the sale of your personal information through an Authorized Agent, we will require that you or the Authorized Agent provide us with a valid written authorization executed by you and that Authorized Agent, with the validity of such document determined by us in our reasonable, good faith discretion. Please submit such documentation to us by emailing us at: support@protectamerica.com; or sending us U.S. mail to: Protect America, 3800 Quick Hill Road, Building 1-100, Austin, TX 78728.We endeavor to act on all opt-out requests as soon as practicable, but in all cases within fifteen (15) days of the receipt of your request.Access to Specific Information and Data Portability RightsYou have the right to request that we disclose certain information to you about our collection and use of your personal information over the past twelve (12) months. Once we receive and confirm your verifiable CA User request, we will disclose to you:The categories of personal information we collected about you.The categories of sources for the personal information we collected about you.Our business or commercial purpose for collecting or selling that personal information.The categories of third parties with whom we have shared that personal information.The specific pieces of personal information we collected about you (also called a data portability request).If we sold or disclosed your personal information for a business purpose, two separate lists disclosing:sales, identifying the personal information categories that each category of recipient purchased; anddisclosures for a business purpose, identifying the personal information categories that each category of recipient obtained.Deletion Request RightsYou have the right to request that we delete any of your personal information that we collected from you and retained, subject to certain exceptions. Once we receive and confirm your verifiable CA User request, we will delete (and direct our service providers to delete) your personal information from our (their) records, unless an exception applies.We may deny your deletion request if retaining the information is necessary for us or our service providers to:Complete the transaction for which we collected the personal information, provide a good or service that you requested, take actions reasonably anticipated within the context of our ongoing business relationship with you, or otherwise perform our obligations in connection with our contract with you.Detect security incidents, protect against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent or illegal activity, or prosecute those responsible for such activities.Debug products to identify and repair errors that impair existing intended functionality.Exercise free speech rights, ensure the right of another CA User to exercise their free speech rights or exercise another right provided for by law.Comply with the California Electronic Communications Privacy Act (Cal. Penal Code § 1546 seq.).Engage in public or peer-reviewed scientific, historical, or statistical research in the public interest that adheres to all other applicable ethics and privacy laws, when the information's deletion may likely render impossible or seriously impair the research's achievement, if you previously provided informed consent.Enable solely internal uses that are reasonably aligned with CA User expectations based on your relationship with us.Comply with a legal obligation.Make other internal and lawful uses of that information that are compatible with the context in which you provided it.Exercising Access, Data Portability and Deletion RightsTo exercise your access, data portability and/or deletion rights described above, please submit a verifiable CA User request to us by either:Clicking here;Emailing us at: support@protectamerica.com;Calling us at: (800) 951-5111; orSending us U.S. mail to: Protect America, 3800 Quick Hill Road, Building 1-100, Austin, TX 78728.Only you or a person registered with the California Secretary of State that you authorize to act on your behalf, may make a verifiable CA User request related to your personal information. Where you make a data deletion request, data portability request and/or information access request through an authorized agent, we will require that you or the authorized agent provide us with a valid written authorization executed by both parties, with the validity of such document determined by us in our reasonable, good faith discretion. Please submit such documentation to us by emailing us at: support@protectamerica.com; or sending us U.S. mail to: Protect America, 3800 Quick Hill Road, Building 1-100, Austin, TX 78728.You may only make a verifiable CA User request for access or data portability twice within a 12-month period. The verifiable CA User request must:Provide sufficient information that allows us to reasonably verify that you are the person about whom we collected personal information or an authorized representative.Describe your request with sufficient detail that allows us to properly understand, evaluate, and respond to it.We cannot respond to your request or provide you with personal information if we cannot verify your identity or authority to make the request and confirm that the personal information relates to you. Making a verifiable CA User request does not require you to create an account with us. We will only use personal information provided in a verifiable CA User request to verify the requestor's identity or authority to make the request.Response Timing and FormatWe endeavor to respond to all verifiable CA User requests within forty-five (45) days of the receipt thereof. If we require more time (up to ninety (90) days), we will inform you of the reason and extension period in writing. We will deliver our written response by mail or electronically, at your option. Any disclosures we provide will only cover the twelve (12) month period preceding the receipt of your verifiable request. The response we provide will also explain the reasons we cannot comply with a request, if applicable. For data portability requests, we will select a format to provide your personal information that is readily useable and should allow you to transmit the information from one entity to another entity without hindrance.We do not charge a fee to process or respond to your verifiable CA User request unless it is excessive, repetitive, or manifestly unfounded. If we determine that the request warrants a fee, we will tell you why we made that decision and provide you with a cost estimate before completing your request.Non-DiscriminationWe will not discriminate against you for exercising any of your CCPA rights. Unless permitted by the CCPA, we will not:Deny you goods or services;Charge you different prices or rates for goods or services, including through granting discounts or other benefits, or imposing penalties;Provide you with a different level or quality of goods or services; and/orSuggest that you may receive a different price or rate for goods or services or a different level or quality of goods or services.Changes to these ProvisionsWe reserve the right to amend these Provisions in our discretion and at any time. When we make changes to this Privacy Notice, we will notify you by email or through a notice on the Site’s homepage.Contact InformationIf you have any questions or comments about these Provisions, our Privacy Policy, the ways in which we collect and use your personal information, your choices and rights regarding such use, or wish to exercise your rights under California law, please do not hesitate to contact us by either:Clicking here;Emailing us at: support@protectamerica.com;Calling us at: (800) 951-5111; orSending us U.S. mail to: Protect America, 3800 Quick Hill Road, Building 1-100, Austin, TX 78728.Call Us Today Toll-Free:1-800-951-5111 or e-mail us atinfo@protectamerica.comVisit Us At:Protect America, Inc. 3800 Quick Hill Road, Building 1-100 Austin, TX 78728closeThe security you deserve at the lowest price, guaranteed.Get a Free Quote Free Quote
